pokecommunity.com 2019-12-10

# PokéCommunity Privacy Policy

Policy for how we collect and process your personal information on PokéCommunity and our services.

## Welcome to PokéCommunity!

This is how we handle information we learn about you from your visit to PokéCommunity. What information we receive and use depends on what you do when you visit our site.

## 1: Overview

The PokéCommunity collects data from each visitor to the site and uses it to help us best serve content to readers. Some of that data is collected automatically from all guests and members, while other information is provided to us by members during the sign-up process and as they fill out their profile on the site. Please take the time to read through this policy in full to understand how we obtain and use your data and what options you have to control this use. If you have any questions or concerns after reading this, feel free to contact us using one of the methods listed at the end of this document.

## 2: Data We Collect

During your use of PokéCommunity to browse, view, or participate in conversations between our members or view news, we may collect certain information from you.

### Information you provide to us

You do not have to create an account to access basic service features such as browsing threads or reading information. If you choose to create an account, you will need to provide us with personal data. This personal data identifies, or could reasonably be used to identify, you as an individual. Depending on which service you use, we may collect different information about you. This personal data includes:

  * **An account username** , used to identify you on PokéCommunity, which is always public, but you may choose to use a pseudonym;
  * **Contact details** , such as your email address; and,
  * **Other personal data** , such as your date of birth and gender.

You are responsible for the content of your posts and contributions to our site and services, so be careful not to reveal any sensitive information. If you ever need to edit a post, the previous text will be retained for up to 30 days before being automatically deleted. If you want to permanently delete a post, contact an administrator and they will be happy to help you. If one of your posts was quoted and you wish for the content in the quote to be removed, contact a moderator or an administrator to manually do this for you.

### Information we collect automatically

For operational purposes, for all visitors to PokéCommunity and its associated services, we collect the name of the domain and host from which you access the internet (for example, verizon.net or princeton.edu) and its associated internet protocol (IP) address; the browser software you use and your operating system; the date and time you access our site; and the internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our site.

## 3: How We Use Data

We use this information to measure the number of visitors to the different sections of our site(s), to track usage, and to help us make our site more useful. Your contact details are used to verify access to your account and as a means for us to send you information about the community.

Occasionally we will publish some user data outside of this website, such as announcing contest winner usernames on our social media accounts or highlighting threads and posts on Discord or other off-site platforms. If you are included in such a post and wish for it to be removed, contact an administrator. In the case of a sponsored competition, we may share details such as username or email address of winners with the sponsor and by entering the contest, you opt-in to have your information shared with the sponsor. A contest of this kind will always be clarified in its announcement and rules.

## 4: About Local Device Storage (including the use of “Cookies”)

Websites, including PokéCommunity, use your device’s local storage to store information used to provide enhanced functionality to their users, often in the form of cookies. The ability to store data on a user’s device helps website providers with understanding how people use a website, remembering a user’s login details, and storing website preferences. 

A “cookie” is a small text file that a website can place on your computer's hard drive in order to collect information about your activities on the site or to make it possible to remember your settings and login status. The cookie transmits this information back to the PokéCommunity server which, generally speaking, is the only computer that can read it. If you want to know when this happens, or to prevent it from happening, you may set up your browser to warn or reject when a website attempts to store a cookie on your local storage.

What PokéCommunity stores using local device storage:

  * **For non-account holders** , PokéCommunity uses a unique, expiring cookie that keeps track of a “session” to keep track of threads that you’ve viewed, which generally expires when the browser is closed. PokéCommunity also uses a cookie to track the last time you’ve visited the site, in order to help accurately flag content you may not have read. Cookies may also be used to store certain site preferences such as “light mode” and “dark mode” page layouts and “themes”.
  * **For account holders** , sign-in information is kept to allow PokéCommunity to authenticate you and allow similar data for non-account holders to be stored on your account. Certain site preferences may still be stored via cookies.

## 5: Choice and Access

For individuals residing in the United States, the _Freedom of Information Act_ and the _Privacy Act of 1974_ provides you certain rights to obtain personal information about you from our records. For individuals residing within member states of the European Union, your rights to access and consent to the usage of your data are provided by the [_General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679_](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=celex%3A32016R0679).

We offer all users some control over the privacy of the information associated with their account. Users may choose which optional elements of their profile will be filled out, such as location, interests, friend codes, and more.

They may also choose which elements of their profile will be visible to whom, with options ranging from all guests and registered users, registered users only, to users in one's friend list. Users may also choose which user information appears with each of their posts on the forum. After registration, it is optional to display age and date of birth to the public or to other users.

Only staff have access to extended personally identifying information, such as your IP address, and this is only for the purpose of moderation. They also have the ability to see private profile fields, such as date of birth and visitor messages, also for the purpose of moderation.

In very limited circumstances, we may be required by law to disclose information you submit to our attorneys or law enforcement.

## 6: Third-Party Partners

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. To do so, these companies may place a tracking cookie or similar tracking technologies on your browser. These companies may use the information they collect about your online use to recognize you across the devices you use and make decisions about the advertising that you may be shown. To learn more about this behavioral advertising or opt out of the practice, please visit the [Network Advertising Initiative’s opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/) on any devices you access PokéCommunity from.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to you based on your visit to our site and other sites on the internet. You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy (<https://policies.google.com/privacy>).

We use Stripe to process payments when we take donations. The information we receive through Stripe will only be used to connect your payment to your account in order to grant supporter benefits. When using Stripe to donate to PokéCommunity, you must agree to their privacy policy (<https://stripe.com/us/privacy>).

This website links to documents or pages located on websites maintained by various other organizations. Once you access a link to another website, you are subject to the privacy policy of the website containing that page.

## 7: Use of PokéCommunity by Minors

Account creation on PokéCommunity is restricted to individuals age 13 or over. The site may be viewed by minors younger than this, but they may not create an account or interact with other members. We are not responsible for age-inappropriate content for minors who browse the PokéCommunity.

If you are located in the European Union, by law you must be age 16 or over or have parental permission to register an account with us.

## 8: Jurisdiction

PokéCommunity is a non-commercial, hobby-based fan website and all actions performed on this site, about this site, or any related activity, reflects that fact. Users assume any and all liability for any use of this site within the laws of California and the United States.

Should we make any changes to this document in the future, we will notify all registered users.

If you have any queries about our privacy policy, or you want to check or remove information from our files, you may contact us. Our contact details are below.

When you contact us, we may require some level of identification in order to respond to or investigate your complaint or request. This is so we can ensure you are the owner of an account, if applicable. If you do not have an account, your contact information will be used to facilitate communication about your issue. We do not share information received in this manner with any third parties.

We may be contacted by email, using our secure “Contact Us” Form:

<https://www.pokecommunity.com/sendmessage.php>

For minor questions and concerns, you may use our Feedback & Support forum, although any post you make there may be read by any other visitor, both guests and account holders:

<https://www.pokecommunity.com/forumdisplay.php?fn=support>

Policy last updated April 20th, 2019, 3:45 PM (local time).
